Piyush Biswal

Senior Full Stack Developer

A Digital Transformation Consultant with more than 5 years of experience with Fortune 500 and Big 4 companies. Collaborated with multiple customer entities to conceptualize and implement their digital journey, innovation factories, Digital workplace, and complete end to end digital product development. Conceptualized and implemented various Enterprise solutions and products with niche business value proposition and a very high ROI. An Innovation Catalyst- Tech Afficiando



Sequelize ORM

piyush.rvk@gmail.com

+918792151911

piyush-repo.github.io

S live:piyushbiswal

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (Jul 2018 - Present)

Eze Software India Pvt Ltd.

An US based Fin-tech Investment Management Suite Product Development company, specially nurturing products for Buy and Sell Side with 1800+ clients

- Working as a FullStack Developer for the Commissions Product, driving it from end to end along with CI/CD pipelines.
- Developed an important feature which led to the on boarding of multiple clients and brought revenues to the company.
- Added value to the development process and delivery by working on cross team products with latest Coding standards.
- Running business analysis meetings, gathering requirements and designing solutions along with the team.
- Prepare estimates for new projects and work with the Product Manager on planning of new features and enhancements.
- Building user stories and Delivering solutions in Agile Scrum.
- · Collaborated with QA's for testing of user stories.

Senior Software Engineer (June 2018 - May 2018) Mobinius Technology

ChatBot, Web and Mobile App development

- Worked as a Node JS Backend Developer along with the team for development of apps which includes a Contract management system, Minicampus (An EdTech platform), Timesheet management and Qart (An Ecommerce IOS Mobile App).
- Implemented Job Schedulers for automation Data Sync and triggering alerts .
- Producer of Node Js Express framework based Rest API service Endpoints along with Consuming it from Angular Application end.
- Worked for API documentation for QA Client reference.
- Worked on load testing of Rest API endpoints .
- Implemented JWT token based authentication and session management for API's.
- Took active role for deployment of apps into Production, Staging and Testing Environments.
- RA and documentation from Clients and PR reviews .
- POC on Chat Bots using Google Dialog Flow.

SVC Info Developer (March 2014 - June 2017)

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Enterprise Product & Solution

- Developed anIntuitive Dashboard for displaying the Real Time Key Metrics like Change management for an Telecom Giant.
- Worked in a Data warehousing Project and developed Reports focused on seeing

SKILLS



Mongoose ORM

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Node Project Scaffolding 🗗

Translator With IBM Watson 🗹

EDUCATION

BE In Electronics & Telecom(2009-13) BPUT - CGPA - 8.5 /10

ORGANIZATIONS

Organization Name

INTERESTS

Interest